

Greater NYC Area

□ (718)-717-9860 | **□** psaha5@binghamton.edu | **☆** www.pitom.xyz | **□** pitoms | **□** pitoms

Summary_

New grad with full-time software engineering experience specializing in Web Technologies and OOP back-end, front-end development. Loves JavaScript, C++, Linux and OS X. Interested in developing intuitive UI solutions to boost sales and user retention. Interested in tackling complex problems and finding efficient and effective solutions. Flexible learner and can rapidly pick up new frameworks and technologies.

Strong foundation in the following programming languages, frameworks and technologies:

- Java, JDBC, C, C++, Php, Python, TypeScript, Javascript, HTML 5, CSS 3
- Angular 6, React, Vue, Spring, Node.js, JQuery
- · SQL, MongoDB, Heroku, AWS, Azure, Docker, Jenkins, Github, Cloud Deployment, Linux, Mac OS, Windows

Education

Binghamton University

Binghamton, New York

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Aug. 2016 - May. 2020

 Algorithms, Computer Architecture, Data Structures, Network Programming, Cyber Security, Internet Of Things, Operating Systems, Design Patterns, Discrete Mathematics & Probability, Linear Algebra

Work Experience _____

Vettery New York, New York

DATA SCIENCE & BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE INTERN

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- · Audited Vettery's use of Data Visualization tool ChartlO and presented insights on transitioning to a new tool.
- Analyzed datasets with the aid of Data Science and Business Intelligence teams to provide meaningful insights on business problems.
- · Tracked performance of a new product feature and collaborated with team leads to define success metrics.

Binghamton VP of Finance

Binghamton, New York

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sep. 2017 - May 2018

Jan. 2016 - Present

- Optimized clerical workflow by 9% with intelligent character recognition tool (Tesseract).
- Implemented Views and Indexes to decrease SQL database latency. Decreased front-end page load time by 6%
- Developed two-factor authentication login system to increase security of financial data.

ScholarStem (Startup)

New York, New York

• Lead Teacher

• Led after-school coding courses for groups of 20 – 30 students at various middle schools across New York City.

- Translated tough CS concepts into byte size digestible ideas.
- Inspired students to own their work and become excited about the future of technology.
- Created relations with executive directors of non-profits to schedule ScholarStem's services at schools.

Personal Projects_

AlgoComparator

BEING BUILT WITH C++

• Developing a visualization platform that shows how popular algorithms behave when given diverse data-sets.

Dynamic Memory Allocation Library

BUILT IN C ON LINUX

• Implemented Malloc, Realloc, and Free functions. The functions use the linked-lists best-fit algorithm for memory management.

Halo Mirror

BUILT IN NODE.JS ON LINUX

• Developed software for a futuristic smart mirror in Node.js. Built on top of open-source MagicMirror code. Top-rated product among a pool of 30 IoT devices.